

Sathiyanarayanan Palani

Senior Engineer (Software / Automation Development)

About Me

Hello!

I'm Sathiyanarayanan Palani.

I am a senior Python Developer with adequate knowledge in C & C++.

I've worked as SDET & DevOps Engineer for development of embedded software Applications.

Age 26

Email sathiyanarayanan396@gmail.com

Phone +918072500974

Address 18/26 Rathna Nagar, Alpet,

Manjakuppam, Cuddalore,

TamilNadu, India

Professional Skills

Python Proficiency in Communication

C/C++ Self-Learning/Problem-Solving

Jenkins/Docker Proof-of-concept development

Skills

Category Technologies

Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, Shell & Batch basics

Operating System: Linux, windows

Communication

Networking Protocols:

Protocols:

UART, I2C, SPI

Source Code

Management:

3

git Git, 🖸 Github

TCP/IP, UDP, HTTP, MQTT, SQL

Tools and Libraries: Gtest, FFF, Jenkins, Git, MySQL, OpenCV, Tkinter, paramiko, SCP, pandas, ASTREE, lark – parser, matplotlib,

numpy

Web Technologies: Node.js, react.js mui basics

DevOps: Jenkins, Docker, kubernetes basics

https://pypi.org/

Work Experience (4.5+ years)

Test Automation Engineer at MBRDI, Bangalore (as External)

May, 2021 - Dec, 2021

• Responsible for writing test scripts for automated validation of measurement in python.

Process Automation Engineer at MBRDI, Bangalore (as External)

Jan, 2020 - Apr, 2021

- Responsible for development of Custom framework and reusable components in python for automated test case generation using pandas data frames.
- · Responsible for Automation of test case generation using Custom Python framework and Bash.
- Responsible for HiL process Automation via SSH using python Libraries like paramiko and SCP.

Software Validation Engineer at MBRDI, Bangalore (as External)

Apr, 2019 - Dec, 2019

- Responsible for unit testing, L2 testing using Google test framework.
- · Responsible for Runtime dynamic analysis of c using ASTREE.

Python Developer at SAFRAN, Bangalore (as External)

Oct, 2018 - Mar, 2019

- Responsible for Multi-Display Broadcast over local Network using TCP/IP.
- Responsible for Data Visualization of sensor plots in Aerospace Applications using python & plotly (3d scalar plots).
- Responsible for visualization of volumetric data in the form of normal distribution for the development of algorithm on event classification.

Embedded Software Developer at iElektron Technologies, Chennai

Jul, 2017 - Sep, 2018

- Responsible for Embedded Software unit and functional Testing.
- Responsible for Embedded Software Development of iElektron Security Products.
- Development of multi-branch CI/CD pipeline in Jenkins for Unit Testing with github app integration for events and mail, slack integration for notifications.
- Responsible for development of semi-automated hardware testing platform for Renesas Microcontrollers using Iron-python Renesas APIs

Education

BE - Electrical and Electronics Engineering from Anand Institute of Higher Technology, chennai (affiliated to Anna University)

2013 - 2017

- Graduated with a first class in Electrical and Electronics Engineering.
- Final Year project done using OpenCV and Raspberry Pi for Automatic Attendance System using Face Recognition.

HSC from ARLM Matric Higher Secondary School, Cuddalore

2012 - 2013

• Completed with 85%

SSLC from SRV Matric Higher Secondary School, Trichy

2010 - 2011

• Completed with 85%